《超凡蜘蛛侠》
5 4 3
Five, four, three...
2 1
...two, one.
准备好了吗 我来咯
Ready or not, here I come.
嗨 爸爸
Hey, Dad?
爸爸
Dad!
你得跟你的
You'll stay with Aunt May...
伯父伯母住一阵子
...and Uncle Ben for a little while.
- 我想和你们一起 - 不行
- I wanna go with you. - No.
做三明治要去掉面包皮
Doesn't like crust on his sandwiches...
晚上睡觉他喜欢留点光
...and he likes to sleep with a little light on.
- 玛丽 走吧 走吧 - 我的天
- Mary. Come on, come on. - Oh, God.
爸爸
Dad.
要听话
Be good.
抱歉
Sorry.
早上好 弗莱舍
Morning, Flash.
早上好 帕克
Good morning, Parker.
嘿 你是彼得 是吧
Hey. It's Peter, right?
我非常喜欢你的照片
I really like your photos.
哦 谢谢 谢谢
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
我想问
Listen...
你周五晚上有空吗
...are you busy Friday night?
太好了 你能给我男朋友的车拍些照片么
Cool. Can you take pictures of my boyfriend's car?
你知道的 我就是想挑张好的裱起来
You know, I really wanna frame a good one...
送给他当生日礼物
...for his birthday.
你对他可真好啊 喔 想法非常好
That's really nice of you. wow, that's such a nice thought.
好吧 我会看一下我的
Yeah, I'll have a look at the old....
- 我的时间表 - 好的
- The old schedule. - Okay.
帕克
Parker.
- 怎么了老师 - 你还想要你的滑板么
- Yes, sir? - You want to keep that skateboard?
- 要的 - 那就轮子朝天
- Yeah. - Keep it off the ground.
- 嗯 嗯 - 别着地
- Sure. Yeah. - Wheels up.
这样么
Like that?
- 没错 - 明白了
- That's it. - Okay.
吃掉 吃掉 吃掉
Eat it! Eat it! Eat it!
吃掉 吃掉
Eat it! Eat it!
吃掉 吃掉 吃掉
Eat it! Eat it! Eat it!
把你的菜吃掉 戈登 快点
Eat your vegetables, Gordon. Come on!
赶紧的
Come on!
嘿 帕克 来
Hey, Parker, come on.
拍张照片
Get a picture of this.
不 我不会拍这种照片 把他放下来 哥们
No, I'm not gonna take a picture of it. Put him down, man.
- 来吧 - 戈登 别吃 别吃
- Come on. - Gordon, don't eat it, don't eat it.
拍一张吧
Take the picture.
放他下来 弗莱舍
Put him down, Flash.
拍照片
Take the picture.
放下他 尤金
Put him down, Eugene!
嘿 伙计
Hey, man.
来啊
Come on!
站起来啊帕克
Get up, Parker!
站起来
Get up!
我是不会拍那照片的
Still not taking the picture.
趴着吧 帕克
Stay down, Parker!
谁敢挡我
Who wants one more?
- 来啊 - 弗莱舍
- One more! - Flash!
弗莱舍
Flash...
我们今天放学计划仍旧不变吧
...we still on for after school today?
我家 三点半
My house, 3:30?
我希望你做了作业
I hope you did homework.
上一次
Last time, I was...
我对你可非常失望
...disappointed in you.
- 行啊 闪开 - 不 咱先去上课怎么样
- Okay, move. - No, how about we go to class?
怎么样
How about it?
随便
Whatever.
我觉得你刚刚做的很棒
I thought that was great what you did.
有点傻
It was stupid...
但很棒
...but it was great.
你最好去一趟医务室 你可能会得脑震荡
You should go to the nurse. You might have a concussion.
你叫什么
What's your name?
你不知道我的名字吗
You don't know my name?
不 我知道
No, I know your name.
但我想知道你还知不知道
I want to know if you know your name.
彼得
Peter.
- 帕克 彼得?帕克 - 好的 好 很好
- Parker. Peter Parker. - Okay. Okay, good.
要是我还是会去医务室的
I'd still go to the nurse though.
你是格温 对吗
You're Gwen, right?
格温·斯泰茜
Gwen Stacy.
好吧
All right.
嘿
Hey.
今晚做意面和肉丸
I'm making spaghetti and meatballs tonight.
你确定吗 意大利面和肉丸
You're serious? Spaghetti and meatballs.
你什么时候开始不喜欢意面和肉丸的
Since when don't you like spaghetti and meatballs, huh?
- 哦我的天 - 怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What's up?
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your face?
没事 摔一跤而已 滑板的时候
I'm all right. Just-- I fell, skating.
没事的
It's all right.
本恩·帕克 你想把这脏兮兮的盒子
Ben Parker, don't you even...
丢在我的厨房里门都没有
...think about leaving that filthy box in my kitchen.
这些可是我的保龄球奖品
My bowling trophies.
哦 好吧 那当然可以了
Oh, well, then, by all means...
请一定要把这脏兮兮的盒子放在厨房里
...Ieave that box in my kitchen.
- 发生什么事了你 - 他摔倒了
- What happened to you? - He fell.
我从来都搞不懂小屁孩为什么要玩那些玩意
Why you kids ride those things, I'll never know.
因为那很傻很危险
Because it's stupid and dangerous.
还记得我们犯傻的时候么
Remember when we were stupid and dangerous?
不记得了
No.
- 相信我 我们是过来人 - 好吧 很高兴知道
- Trust me, we were. - All right. Good to know.
哪里发洪水了
Where's the flood?
跟上 我带你去
Follow me. I'll show you.
- 你确定 - 当然
- You serious? - Yes.
好吧
All right.
应该是冷凝器
Think it's the condenser tray.
水太多 损坏了冷凝器或者热传导管道系统
Too much water for the condenser tray or the heat exchange tubing.
肯定是没过水位线了
This has got to be the fill line.
只有这才说的通
That's the only thing that makes any sense.
你能修好吗
Can you fix it?
不 今晚不行 我明天去趟五金店
No, not tonight. I'll go by the hardware store tomorrow.
好极了 顺便把这个敷脸上
Good deal. And meanwhile, put this on your face.
另一个动手的家伙怎样了
How's the other guy look?
得了吧 我一看就知道怎么回事了
Come on. I know a right cross when I see one.
说还是不说 要我打小报告给你爹地么
Yes or no? Do I have to call somebody's father?
别 别
No, no.
好吧
All right.
我不会告诉你梅伯母的
Well, I wouldn't tell your Aunt May.
惹火她的小鬼都太可怜了
I pity the poor kid who'd have to suffer her wrath.
嘿 你上来之前 再看看
Before you come up, see if...
- 有没有修一下还能再用的东西 - 没问题
- ...there's anything else worth saving. - Okay.
- 水管工不负责修家电啊 - 不 他们也修的
- Plumbers don't fix appliances. - Yes, they do.
他们只负责修管子和抽水
They fix pipes and pump things.
只要你让他们修
If you ask them to--
我都把那东西忘光了
I forgot all about that thing.
那是你爸爸的
It was your dad's.
- 嗯 - 他叫我们替他好好保管
- Yeah. - He asked us to keep it safe.
他在第九大道上的一家皮具店的橱窗里看到的
He saw it in the window of that leather shop over on 9th Avenue.
才19岁 一个19岁的小孩要个公文包干嘛呢
He was 19. What does a 19-year-old kid need with a briefcase?
猜猜谁卖给他的
And guess who sold it to him.
- 我不知道 - 你妈妈
- I don't know. - Your mother.
他们就是这么认识的
That's how they met.
他让你 好好保管 为什么
He asked you to keep this safe? Why?
这里面什么都没有啊
There's nothing in here.
你看过这包么 什么都没有
Have you looked? There's nothing here.
你爸爸是个很神秘的人 彼得
Your father was a very secretive man, Peter.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
这是谁
Who's that?
你知道这是谁么
Do you know who that is?
和你爸爸一起工作的同事 我猜
Some guy who worked with your dad, I guess.
把这从桌上拿开吧 好么
Just take this off the table, all right?
我们吃饭了 拿走 然后去洗手
We're gonna eat. Off. And wash your hands.
- 马上 - 好的
- Now. - All right.
快去吧
Go on.
你要做个好孩子 彼得
I need you to be a good boy. Peter.
你们要去哪
Where are you going?
现在有些事
There's something now...
我和你妈妈有些事必须要去做
...something your mom and I have to do.
这是什么
What is this?
零 零 衰变率算法
"Zero, zero, decay rate algorithm."
好的 马上来 马上
Yeah, one sec, one sec.
请进
Come in.
你还好吗
You okay?
- 好着呢 怎么了 - 哦天啊
- Yeah. What's up? - Oh, my God.
你和他太像了
You look just like him.
- 我能进来吗 - 可以
- Can I come in? - Yeah.
听着
Listen...
我读的书不多
...I don't have much education.
你知道的 彼得
You know that, Peter.
该死 你十岁时做的功课我就已经不知道怎么辅导了
Hell, I stopped being able to help with your homework when you were 10.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is...
我知道爸爸不在身边的日子很难过
...I know it's been rough for you without your dad.
我也知道我们很少谈他们的事
And I know we don't talk much about them.
- 嗯 没关系 - 不 当然有关系
- Yeah, it's all right. - No, it is not all right.
我希望可以改变 但是我不能
I wish I could change it, but I can't.
柯特?康纳斯
Curt Connors.
这是照片上站在你爸旁边那人的名字
That's the name of the guy in the picture with your dad.
他们一起工作了很多年 关系很铁
They worked together for years and they were close.
但那晚之后我们再没见过他
But after that night, we never saw him again.
他甚至没打过电话来
He never even called.
一次都没有
Not once.
去查查看吧
Go figure.
她很漂亮
She's pretty.
本恩伯伯
Uncle Ben.
怎么了
What?
你是个很好的爸爸
You're a pretty great dad.
不好意思
Excuse me.
怎么了
What?
有什么能为您效劳
Can I help you?
哦 呃 我不知道
I don't know. I'm here to see...
- 我是来见康纳斯博士的 - 好的
- ...Dr. Connors. - Right.
在左手边那儿找一下你的名字
You'll find yourself to the left.
你是来这实习的吗
You are here for the internship?
是 是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
找到你的名牌 左手边位置
You'll find your badge to the left.
找不到你自己的吗
Having trouble finding yourself?
没有 我找到了
No. Yeah, I got it.
好的
Okay...
格韦拉先生
...Mr. Guevara.
谢谢
Gracias.
不客气
De Nada.
欢迎来到奥斯集团
Welcome to Oscorp.
由创始人 诺曼?奥斯本 创建
Born from the mind of our founder, Norman Osborn...
奥斯集团大厦有108层 层层都有新科技
... the Oscorp Tower houses 108 floors of innovation.
我们运用科技头脑不断拓宽 防御工程
Our scientific minds are pushing the boundaries of defence, biomedical...
生物医学和化学科技的界限 未来由我们创造
...and chemical technologies. The future lies within.
欢迎来到奥斯集团
Welcome to Oscorp.
我的名字是格温·斯泰茜
I'm Gwen Stacy, a senior...
我是中城科技高中的毕业班学生
...at Midtown Science...
也是康纳斯博士的实习生领队
...and head intern to Dr. Connors.
所以参观期间我会一直和你们在一起
So I'll be with you for the duration of your visit.
我去哪 你们跟到哪
Where I go, you go.
这是基本规矩 你们只要记住这个
That's the rule. Remember that...
- 就一切好说 - 来
- ...all will be fine. - Come on!
要是忘了的话...
lf you forget that--
嘿 听着
Look, listen.
告诉他们真正的罗德里戈?格韦拉在这里
Tell them Rodrigo Guevara is here.
快告诉他们罗德里戈?格韦拉在
Just tell them Rodrigo Guevara is here!
我就是罗德里戈
My name's Rodrigo!
我猜现在不用我说忘了之后的下场了
I guess I don't need to tell you what happens if you forget.
走吧
Shall we?
这边走
Come around this way.
下午好 格温
Good afternoon, Gwen.
康纳斯博士
Dr. Connors.
欢迎
Welcome.
我的名字是柯蒂斯·康纳斯博士
My name is Dr. Curtis Connors.
是的 以防你们疑惑 我是个左撇子
Yes, in case you're wondering, I'm a southpaw.
我不是个残废
I'm not a cripple...
我是个科学家 而且我在世界爬虫学界中首屈一指
...I'm a scientist, and the world's foremost authority on herpetology.
给不明白的人解释一下 也就是爬行动物学
That's reptiles, for those of you who don't know.
就像帕金森病人
Like the Parkinson's patient...
恐惧地看着自己的身体渐渐不听使唤
...who watches on in horror as her body...
或是患有眼部黄斑恶化的病人
...slowly betrays her, or the man with macular degeneration...
视野日渐暗淡 我渴望修复自己
...whose eyes grow dimmer each day, I long to fix myself.
我希望创造一个没有弱点的世界
I want to create a world without weakness.
有人敢猜猜这要如何实现吗
Anyone care to venture a guess just how?
请说
Yes.
干细胞
Stem cells?
有希望 但是
Promising. But the solution...
我想的方法更加 彻底
...I'm thinking of is more radical.
- 没人知道么 - 跨物种遗传学
- No one? - Cross-species genetics.
一旦
Person gets Parkinson's...
产生多巴胺的脑细胞开始消失
...when the brain cells that produce dopamine...
人们就会患上帕金森
...start to disappear.
但是斑马鱼
But a zebra fish has the ability...
有令细胞再生的能力
...to regenerate cells on command.
如果你能想办法
If you could give this ability...
把这能力给予你提到的那个女人 那么
...to the woman you're talking about, that's that. She's....
她就能治愈自己
She's curing herself.
是的 你只要给她脖子上装个腮就行了
Yeah, you just have to look past the gills on her neck.
你是
And you are...
他是中城科技
He's one of Midtown Science's...
- 最聪明的学生之一 - 真的吗
- ...best and brightest. - Really?
他是班上的第二名
Second in his class.
- 第二名 - 是的
- Second? - Yeah.
你确定吗
Sure about that?
非常确定
I'm pretty sure.
不好意思有事要处理 你们就跟着才华洋溢的斯泰茜小姐吧
I'm afraid duty calls. I'll leave you in the more-than-capable hands of Miss Stacy.
很高兴见到你们
Nice meeting you all.
你们可以过来围过来
If you'd like to gather round.
欢迎来到奥斯集团生命树
Welcome to Oscorp's tree of life.
我们星球的生命树是十分混乱
Our planet's tree of life is immense.
在奥斯集团的
At Oscorp's...
- 跨物种部门中 - 嗨
- ...Cross-Species Division... - Hi.
我们努力探索激动人心的新研究方法
...we endeavour to explore exciting new methods....
你在干嘛呢 罗德里戈
What are you doing, "Rodrigo"?
哦对
Oh, yeah.
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我在这工作 我不是
I work here. I don't.
我打算说我在这工作的
I was gonna say I work here...
但似乎实际上你是在这工作的 所以你其实知道我不在这工作
...but it seems like you do work here. So you know that I don't.
你跟踪我吗
You following me?
不是 我没有跟踪你 我可不知道你在这工作
No, I'm not following you, no. I had no idea you worked here.
那你为什么在这里呢
Why would you be here?
我偷溜进来是因为
I just snuck in because....
我爱科学
I love science.
- 你爱科学 - 我爱死它了
- You love it. - I'm passionate about it.
你偷溜进来
So you snuck in...
- 我得带这组参观 - 我懂
- I have to lead this tour group. - I know.
晚点我再详细问你 别给我添麻烦
I'll ask you more about this later. Do not get me in trouble.
- 我保证不会的 - 跟紧队伍
- I promise you I won't. - Stay with the group.
好了 同学们 我要带你们去生物反应堆房间了
All right, guys? I'm gonna take you to the bioreactor room now.
抱歉 哟
Sorry. Yo.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们今早收到了信使核糖核酸序列的结果
We received the results from the mRNA sequences this morning.
很令人失望
They were disappointing.
什么叫令人失望
Define "disappointing."
又一个死链
Another dead end.
是衰变率算法
It's the decay rate algorithm.
- 这是预料之中的 - 预料之中
- And this is to be expected. - Expected?
你说就快成功了
You said you were close.
是很快了 但是也要花点时间
We are close, but it's gonna take time.
他没时间了
He doesn't have time.
诺曼?奥斯本快死了 康纳斯博士
Norman Osborn is dying, Dr. Connors.
救他
Save him.
不然咱都得掉脑袋
Or we'll both lose our heads.
好吧 给我名牌
All right, give me the badge.
给我
Give it to me.
对不起
Sorry.
真恶心 我现在一身啤酒味
Disgusting. Now I smell like beer.
对不起 我不是故意的
I didn't mean to do that.
我不是
I didn't mean to....
我不是 我不
I didn't-- I didn't--
把你的手从她身上拿开
Get your hand off her!
我在努力拿开
I'm trying to get my....
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你玩我吗
Are you kidding me?
- 嘿 揍他 鲁迪 - 嘿
- Hey, get him, Rudy! - Hey!
伙计 对不起
Man, I'm sorry!
伙计 你没事吧
Man, are you all right?
- 撂倒他 - 上啊
- Take him down! - Come on.
揍他 老兄 揍他
Get him, man! Get him!
别 亲 别动我的滑板
No, man, no. Not my board.
拜托 哥们儿 别
Please, dude, don't--
对不起
Sorry!
对不起 对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
科尼岛 到站了
Coney Island, next stop.
下一站终点站 科尼岛
Next and final stop, Coney Island.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
对不起 我回来晚了
Sorry. I'm late.
- 我去了 - 我们很担心你
- I got-- - We've been so worried.
我知道 对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
注意
Watch out!
那是个苍蝇 彼得
That's a fly, Peter.
没错
Yeah.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry...
让你们等这么晚
...I kept you guys up.
我反应迟钝 我不负责任
I'm insensitive, I'm irresponsible...
我现在很饿
...and I'm hungry.
瑞士肉卷
Meat loaf.
喝多了吗
Drinking?
那是什么
What's this?
应该不是
I don't think so.
这是你的瑞士肉卷
This is your meat loaf.
这是瑞士肉卷里的战斗卷
This beats all other meat loafs.
出大事了
Something is very wrong.
没错
Yeah.
没人喜欢吃你的肉卷
Nobody likes your meat loaf.
我拿得了
I got it.
他拿了冻意粉和冻奶酪
He took the frozen macaroni and cheese.
我看到了
I noticed that.
你为什么不告诉我你不喜欢我的瑞士肉卷
Why didn't you tell me you didn't like my meat loaf?
37年前你就该告诉我了
You could have said that to me 37 years ago.
我都做了多少瑞士肉卷给你了
How many meat loafs have I made for you?
彼得
Peter.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我
I'm....
在做作业
Homework.
小心点
Be careful.
好的
Sure.
康纳斯博士
Dr. Connors.
你不记得我了 我
You don't remember me. I--
你是那天的实习生
The intern from the other day.
是的 没错 是的
Yeah, yeah. That's right, yeah.
我确定你非常优秀 但这是我家
I'm sure you're very nice, but this is a home.
我想请你到我办公室预约
I ask you to make an appointment with my office.
我是理查德?帕克的儿子
I'm Richard Parker's son.
彼得
Peter?
我恐怕帮不了你多少 彼得
I'm afraid I can't help you much.
我不知道为什么他们离开 也不知道他们去了哪
I don't know why they left or where they were going.
反应很快
Good reflexes.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
- 谢谢你 - 我读了你的书
- Thank you. - I read your book.
嗯
Yeah.
写得很好
It's something, you know.
这么说你真的
So you really think...
- 觉得有可能么 跨物种遗传学 - 是的 当然了
- ...it's possible, cross-species genetics? - Yes, of course.
外界都在嘲笑你父亲和我研究出的理论
Your father and l were mocked for our theories.
不止是广大群众 也包括奥斯集团
Not just in the community at large, but at Oscorp, as well.
他们叫我们疯子科学家
They called us mad scientists.
然后你父亲繁殖了蜘蛛
And then your father bred the spiders...
一切都改变了
...and everything changed.
结果大出所料
The results were beyond encouraging.
简直是惊世之举
They were spectacular.
我们本可以改变无数人的命运
We were gonna change the lives of millions.
也包括我的
Including my own.
然后就结束了
Then it was over.
他走了
He was gone.
带着他的研究
Took his research with him.
而我知道 没有他我
And I knew without him, l....
我
I....
我很生气
I was angry.
所以我远离你
So I stayed away from you...
和你的家庭
...and your family.
这一点我真的很抱歉
And for that, I'm truly sorry.
假如说
Say....
假如说这起作用了
Say it worked.
你们成功了
Say you got it to work.
人类会继承多少外来物种的能力
Like, how much would the foreign species take over?
副作用会是什么
What could the side effects be?
很难说 因为还没有试验品幸存下来
It's hard to say, considering no subject survived.
问题总是出在
The problem was always--
衰变率算法上
The decay rate algorithm?
- 是的 - 好的
- Right. - Right.
我能不能
Can I...
当然
Of course.
绝世之才啊
Extraordinary.
你怎么想出来的
How did you come up with this?
彼得 你哪天放学后来大楼里
Peter, how about coming to see me at the Tower...
- 和我见个面好吗 - 好的
- ...one day after school? - Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
一号 雷吉
Number one, Reggie.
传球 兄弟
Run it, buddy.
上吧 雷吉
Let's go, Reggie.
不合格
Rejected!
你故意的吧 弗莱舍
You did that on purpose, Flash!
故意的就好了 你最好小心着点
I should've. You better watch your back.
嘿
Hey.
没事吧
All right?
交出来 帕克
Give it up, Parker.
快点 伙计
Come on, man.
等等
One sec.
- 丢过来 伙计 - 你干嘛不来我这拿呢
- Come on, man. - Why don't you take it from me?
就这样 拿走
That's right. Take it.
来啊 拿走吧
Go ahead. Take it.
快拿走啊
Just take it.
好吧 要不这样
All right, how about this?
行了吗
All right?
这样行了吧
How about that?
- 快点啊 弗莱舍 - 弗莱舍 别玩了
- Come on, Flash. - Flash, stop playing, man.
- 快拿过来 - 快点 弗莱舍 快拿走
- Take it from him! - Come on, Flash. Take it.
哟 弗莱舍 快啊
Yo, Flash, let's go.
- 快点 - 拿过来 弗莱舍
- Let's go! - Do it, Flash.
- 别玩了 伙计 - 快点 弗莱舍
- Stop playing, man. - Let's go, Flash.
- 你在干嘛呢 - 怎么了
- What are you doing? - What's up?
你搞啥啊
What you doing?
好了 来吧 来啊帕克 上啊
All right, bring it! Come on, Parker! Come on!
彼得的行为
Peter's behaviour is just...
可不值得提倡
...unacceptable.
他们不会叫我们
They won't make us pay...
- 赔那个篮板的 - 我才不管那篮板呢
- ...for the backboard. - I don't care about the backboard.
- 是真的么 - 啥
- Was that true? - What?
我刚刚听到的啊
What I heard in there just now.
你羞辱了那男孩
Did you humiliate that boy?
对 没错
Yeah, I did.
- 但是 - 但是什么
- But-- - But what?
- 那家伙活该 - 是吗
- This guy deserved it. - Did he?
- 是的 - 他是打你的那孩子么
- Yeah. - ls he the kid that hit you?
是他吗
Is he?
是 是的 但是
Yeah, yeah, but....
所以这就是为了报复
So all this is about getting even.
要是这样 我猜你现在肯定觉得自己特牛逼 是吗
If so, I guess you must feel pretty good about yourself now, right?
我说的对不对
Am I right or wrong?
嗯 我看你就这么想的
Yeah, I thought so.
哼 多亏了你这出小恶作剧
Well, thanks to this little escapade of yours...
我才不得不跟同事换班
...I had to change shifts at work...
所以你今晚9点得去接梅伯母 明白吗
...so you have to pick up Aunt May tonight at 9:.00. Understood?
- 听清楚了吗 - 是的
- ls that understood? - Yeah.
是的 是的
Okay, good.
她看上去挺面熟
She looks familiar.
是你电脑里那姑娘
She's the girl on your computer.
是的
Yeah.
他电脑里有你照片 我是他的缓刑监督官
He's got you on his computer. I'm his probation officer.
别忘了梅伯母
Don't forget Aunt May.
好的
Okay.
他很有个性吧
He's a character.
那是我伯父
That's my uncle.
他就爱胡说
He's a pathological liar.
他把你认错成其他人了
And... He thought you were someone else.
哦天 你电脑里没有我照片么
Oh, man, you don't have me on your computer?
有 我是说 我拍了辩论队的照片 你在辩论队里
Yeah, I mean... I took a photo of the debate team, and you're in the debate team.
- 没错 - 那么
- Right. - So...
他肯定看到了 我在给照片润色
...he must have seen-- I was touching up stuff.
- 润色 - 哎呀
- Touching up stuff? - Come on.
我 我不知道怎么说了
I was.... I'm not gonna answer that.
- 你被开除了么 - 不 不
- Did you get expelled? - No, no.
我没被开除 我得做社区服务
I didn't get expelled. I got community service.
那么 你想不想 我不知道
So you want to-- I don't know...
想干嘛
Want to what?
我不知道
I don't know.
就是
Just....
我不知道 我们可以
I don't know-- We could....
我们可以做点别的事 或者我们可以
We could do something else, or we could--
- 如果你不介意 我们可以 - 好啊
- lf you don't feel like, we could... - Yeah.
- 真的 - 嗯 什么都行
- Yeah? - Yeah, either one.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Really? - Sure.
好
Okay.
好的 很好 听上去很好
All right, good. Sounds good.
太棒了
Cool.
好的
Okay.
- 不是现在 我现在没空 - 嗯
- I can't right now, I can't right now. - Yeah, no.
- 我现在有点忙 - 我知道 我也是
- I'm so busy right now. - I know, me too.
不过也许
But maybe....
- 嗯 你知道 - 其他时间
- Yeah, just, you know.... - Some other....
- 嗯 好的 - 好
- Time, all right. - Okay.
- 回见 - 好的
- Bye. - All right.
我们有蛋白质结构 核糖体DNA
We have protein structure, rDNA...
色层分析 转基因学测试
...chromatography, transgenics testing...
那是X射线图像仪 是这世界上唯一的一台
...that's X-ray video. That's the only one on the planet. We have....
- 那边是人类线谱鉴定器 - 我记得这个
- Human line testing over-- - I remember that.
我见过这个仪器
I've seen that before.
加纳利装置
The Ganali device.
嗯 我记得在我爸爸办公室的一张照片里看到过
Yeah, I remember a picture of that in my dad's office.
原理很简单 在这上面加载一个抗原
The idea was so simple. You load it with an antigen.
它制造的反应云可以覆盖于附近一带 甚至整个城市
It creates a cloud which can be dispersed over a neighbourhood, even a city.
理论上来说 你可以用一个下午治好整个城市里的小儿麻痹
Theoretically, you could cure polio in an afternoon.
难以置信
That's incredible.
但也有人反对使用 万一这个机器加载了某种有毒物质
Well, others disagreed. What if the device were loaded with a toxin?
或者你不想参与治疗了 你也没法
What if you wanted to opt out? You can't...
逃出这个反应云范围 所以它被弃置在此 任尘土掩埋
...run away from a cloud after all, so here it lies, gathering dust.
你在这里看到的 是一只蜥蜴的电脑模型
What you see here is a computer model of a lizard.
许多这样的美妙生物已能完美适应
Many of these wonderful creatures have so brilliantly adapted...
它们可以随意再生出完整的肢体
...that they can regenerate entire limbs at will.
你可以想象我有多妒忌它们
You can imagine my envy.
我们在尝试着驾驭这种能力
We're trying to harness this capability...
把这种能力转到实验对象身上
...and transfer it into our host subject:
弗雷迪 三条腿的老鼠
Freddy the three-legged mouse.
输入方程式吧
Enter the algorithm now.
你要接电话吗
Need to take that?
系统已准备好
System ready...
基因转化
...for gene insertion.
好了
Okay.
来看一下
Check.
然后我们做什么
See what I'm trying to do?
- 替换蛋白质 - 消除免疫反应
- Preempt the proteins. - The immune response.
开始进行
Beginning trials.
等待中 等待中
Pending. Pending.
失败 对象死亡
Failed. Subject deceased.
- 加油 加油 加油 - 等待中
- Come on, come on, come on. - Pending.
失败
Failed.
等待中 失败
Pending. Failed.
对象死亡 等待中
Subject deceased. Pending.
方程式计算成功
Peptide algorithm accepted.
再生完成
Regrowth complete.
- 嘿 - 生命迹象正常
- Hey. - Vitals normal.
血压正常
Blood pressure normal.
断肢再生成功
Limb regeneration successful.
太棒了
Extraordinary.
谢谢你
And thank you.
来见见Fred和Wilma
Meet Fred and Wilma...
我们的三条腿
...our three-legged...
小老鼠
...mice.
拿着
Here you go.
嘿小家伙 抓住你了
Hey, buddy, I got you.
好了
Okay.
当心点 我可不想不小心扎到你
Careful, don't want to stick you by mistake.
人体实验要等到下周才开始
Human trials aren't until next week.
好了
There.
嗨
Hey.
嗨 我以为你
Hey, I thought you....
你是不是忘了什么事儿
Didn't you forget something?
什么
What?
现在 不要接电话 不过我很高兴你的电话没坏
Now, don't answer that, but I'm glad to know it's working.
你欠你姨妈一个道歉
You owe your aunt an apology bigtime.
像个男子汉一样
Be a man.
进屋去 然后道歉
Get in there and apologise.
对不起梅姨妈 我有...
I'm sorry, Aunt May, l....
说真的 你其实
Honestly, you don't have...
不用跟我道歉 你
...to apologise to me. It's your--
- 他必须道歉 - 本恩
- The hell he doesn't. - Ben.
对不起 我有点事耽误了
Look, I'm sorry, I got distracted.
- 哦 你有事耽误了 - 是的
- Oh, he got distracted. - Yeah.
你的姨妈 我妻子 大半夜一个人走了
Your aunt, my wife, had to walk 12 blocks alone...
12个街区 然后一个人等在空荡荡的地铁站
...in the middle of the night and then wait in a deserted subway station...
就是因为你忘记去接她了
...because you got distracted.
本恩 亲爱的 说实话
Ben, sweetheart, honestly...
我可以一个人走回家的
...I am completely capable of walking home--
你不要袒护这个孩子
You will not defend this boy!
- 我不是在袒护他 - 你就是在袒护他
- I'm not defending-- - You are!
- 听好了孩子 - 嗯 我在听
- Listen to me, son. - Yeah, go ahead.
你太像你爸爸了
You're a lot like your father.
一个模子立刻出来的 彼得 这是一件好事
You really are, Peter, and that's a good thing...
不过你父亲有他的人生哲学 还有他自己的原则
...but your father lived by a philosophy, a principle, really.
他相信如果你有能力去帮助别人
He believed that if you could do good things for other people...
那你就有这个道德责任去帮助别人
...you had a moral obligation to do those things.
这就是你生存的意义
That's what's at stake here.
这不是选择
Not choice.
而是责任
Responsibility.
说得挺好的 挺有道理
That is nice. That's great.
你说的都很好 很对 那他现在在哪里
That's all well and good. So where is he?
- 什么 - 他在哪儿
- What? - Where is he?
我爸爸在哪儿
Where's my dad?
站在这里亲口告诉我这些难道不应该是他的责任么
He didn't think it was his responsibility to be here to tell me himself?
别这样 你怎么能这么说
Oh, come on, how dare you?
我怎么敢 你又怎么能这么说
How dare l? How dare you?
你去哪儿
Where you going?
彼得 回来 别这样
Peter, come back here, please.
本恩 让他一个人待一会儿吧 他会没事的
Ben, leave him alone for a little while. He'll be all right.
彼得
Peter!
Peter?
彼得
Peter!
一共2块零7刀
It's $2.07.
这是2块零7刀
是 我知道
Yeah. No, I know.
你挡着后面的人了
Yeah, you're holding up the line. No.
不 你可以付一分钱 但你不能从这里拿
You can leave a penny, you can't take a penny.
- 你说什么 - 你可以随时
- What? - You can leave...
付给我一分钱 但你要想拿走一分
...a penny anytime, you have to spend 10 dollars...
就得交十块 店里的规矩
...to take a penny. It's store policy.
- 你挡着后面的人付钱了 - 我没有2分零钱
- You're holding up my line. - I don't have 2 cents.
你没钱买牛奶就走开 别挡路
You can't afford milk, step aside.
你爸今天没把喝奶的钱给你么
Daddy didn't give you enough milk money today?
说2分钱别扯我爸爸
Just 2 cents...We're talking about 2 cents.
赶紧让开吧 小子
Just step aside, kid.
搞毛啊
Really?
这可不好玩儿
Yo, not cool, bro.
喂 站住
Hey, man, stop!
快来人拦住那个男的
Somebody stop that guy!
嗨 小子 帮个忙
Hey, kid, little help?
跟我没关系
Not my policy.
快来人拦住那个家伙
Somebody stop that dude!
嘿
Hey!
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!
快来人拦住那个家伙
Somebody stop that dude!
嘿
Hey!
噢上帝 上帝啊
Oh, God, oh, God.
快叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
快来人 叫救护车 本恩叔叔 本恩叔叔
Someone call an ambulance! Uncle Ben, Uncle Ben.
噢上帝 噢上帝啊
Oh, God, oh, my God.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
不
No.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
目击者画了一张嫌疑人的画像 请你看一下
Witnesses gave a description to the sketch artist. I need you to take a look.
不 我不认识他
No, I don't know him.
我也料到您并不认得他 女士 凶案组的警官
I didn't expect you would, ma'am. Homicide detectives...
已经在调查了 等等看他们会有什么发现吧
...are on it. We'll see what they turn up.
能把这个给我么
Can I have that?
可以啊
Sure.
还有一件事儿 他左手上有一个
There's one other thing. He has a star...
星星形状的
...tattooed...
纹身
...on his left hand.
彼得 我知道你最近很不好过
Peter, I know things have been difficult lately...
我真的很抱歉
...and I'm sorry about that.
我想我明白你的感受
I think I know what you're feeling.
嗨 帕克
Hey, Parker.
- 别惹我 弗莱舍 - 别这样兄弟 我只是想跟你聊一聊
- Not today, Flash. - Come on, man, I just want to talk.
好受点了 是吧
It feels better, right?
你叔叔去世了
Look, your uncle died.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我听说了
I get it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好吧
Okay?
彼得
Peter.
离他远点
Stay away from him.
- 听见没有 - 嘿
- You understand? - Hey!
- 离乔尼远点 - 喂
- Stay away from Joey. - Hey!
你喜欢打女人是吗
You like beating on girls?
你喜欢打老人是吗
You like beating on old men?
嘿伙计
Hey, pal...
该干嘛干嘛去
...keep walking.
- 这不是你来的地方 - 你上一次出现在皇后区是什么时候
- You're in the wrong place. - When were you in Queens?
我问你话呢
I asked you a question.
尼基 别
Nicky, no!
是这把枪么
That the gun?
你想把我也杀了么
You gonna kill me too?
嘿 别这样
Hey! Stop it!
嘿 住手
Hey, get off!
等等 哦 别打尼基
Wait, oh, don't hit Nicky!
滚远点
Back up!
这家伙疯了
This guy is crazy!
抓到了
Get him!
到这儿来 抓住他
Get back here, man! Get him!
跟着他
Follow him!
- 包围他 伙计 - 我跟着你
- Go around, man! - I'll follow you!
上 上 上
Go, go, go!
他在这儿
There he is!
逃不掉了
Can't get away!
他手臂上有一个星星纹身
He has a star tattooed on his left hand.
哦 来啊
Oh, yeah?
来啊
Come on!
我知道你长什么样子
I know what you look like!
你听见没有
You hear me?
我看见你的脸了
I've seen your face!
你身上就这点钱
Is that all you got?
都给你 放过我
Just take it, take it.
绿恶魔生物缆的设计源于
Engineered from genetically enhanced spiders...
基因强化型蜘蛛 其坚韧度无与伦比
...Oscorp's BioCable tensile strength is unparalleled. We're just beginning...
我们刚刚开始开发它所有潜在的工业应用
... to understand all the potential industrial applications.
一个小钢片就可以安全储存数百米
A single pellet can safely store several hundred metres...
质量轻微的生物缆
...of the lightweight cable.
我的妈啊
Mother....
13号管区各单位注意 在西19号大街和百老汇
Attention, all units in the confines of Precinct 13, receiving a 10-30...
发生一起抢劫案
...on West 19th Street and Broadway.
袭击者是一名白人男性 35岁上下
Assailant is Caucasian male, mid-30s...
体重170到180磅
... 170 to 180 pounds...
及肩金发
...shoulder-length blond hair.
最后看到他时 他正向东步行赶往19号大街
Last seen on foot heading eastbound on 19th Street.
嘿
Hey.
你有看清他的脸吗
You got a description?
没有 他带着面具
Well, no, he wears a mask.
面具
A mask?
他袭击的大部分人
Most of his victims...
都是有前科的重案犯 他们都叫他正义使者
...are suspects with serious rap sheets. They're calling him a vigilante.
好吧 他不是正义使者 他是个无政府主义者
Okay, he's not a vigilante, he's an anarchist.
快来人 帮帮我 逮捕我吧
Help me, somebody! Arrest me!
放我出去
Get me out of here.
嗨 看啊
Hey, look!
弹性纤维 弹性纤维
Spandex. Spandex.
所有东西
Everything...
都是弹性纤维
...spandex.
这种超凡的速度矢量
Extraordinary velocity vector is a function...
是一个质量和加速度的函数
...of both mass and acceleration.
拜托 你比任何人都清楚
Come on, you know better than anyone...
单摆上悬挂物体的质量对于旋转速度是没有影响的
...the weight on any pendulum has no effect on speed.
它不影响频率 但是这绝对是一个动量因素
It doesn't affect frequency, but it's totally a factor in momentum.
喂 梅姨妈
Hey, Aunt May.
嗯 鸡蛋么
Yeah. Eggs?
有机鸡蛋 明白了
Organic, got it.
以后 如果你要偷车
In the future, if you're gonna steal cars...
别穿得像个偷车贼
...don't dress like a car thief, man.
你是什么人 警察么
What are you? You a cop?
啥玩意儿 你真觉得我像是警察吗 哪个警察穿红蓝紧身服
Really? You seriously think I'm a cop? Cop in a skin-tight red-and-blue suit?
你知道吧 你
You know, you're....
你脑子是不是
You've got a mind...
被门挤过啊 先生
...of the true scholar, sir.
是我的话
I was going more for the guys who do the luge.
好主意 好主意
Good thinking. Good thinking.
从窗户那儿出去
Get out the window.
就这样 你出去了
There you go. You got it.
夹住你了
Crotch!
- 让我走 - 这是刀吗
- Just let me go. - ls that a real knife?
对 一把真的刀
Yes, it's a real knife.
我最怕的就是这种小刀了
My weakness, it's small knives.
- 让我走 - 我什么都不怕
- Just let me go. - Anything but...
就怕刀 噢 太没技术含量了
...knives! Oh, it's so simple.
- 帅爆了 - 这是什么
- That was cool. - What is this?
我开发的蜘蛛网 我觉得你并不想知道
Webbing I developed. I don't think you want to know.
摆脱了 让我走
Come on! Let me go!
好 等会儿 就等一秒
Okay, one second. Hold on, one second.
住手 伙计 不要
Knock it off, man. No!
快点 让我走 别玩我了
Come on, let me go. Stop it!
这不好玩
That isn't funny.
- 挺好玩儿的嘛 - 救命
- lt is kind of funny. - Help!
你这样会更麻烦
This could've gone a lot worse.
别动
Now hold still.
蓝衣男孩在这儿
Boys in blue here.
- 哟 我抓住他了 - 不许动
- Yo, I got him. - Freeze!
- 他现在哪儿都去不了 - 别动
- He's not going anywhere. - Don't move.
开玩笑吧
You serious?
你是谁
Who are you?
看来你们不明白我戴面具的意义
No one grasps the concept of the mask.
不许动
Freeze!
我刚替你们完成了80%的工作
I just did 80 percent of your job.
然后呢
And that?
你们就是这样回报我的
That's how you repay me?
呆在那儿别动
Hold it right there!
好吧 这下好玩了
Well, that was fun.
公交车 晚上好啊 亲们
Bus! Hey there, everybody.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
嘿 当心点啊
Hey, watch out.
我在荡秋千
I'm swinging here.
所以 38名纽约市警察
So 38 of New York's finest...
对一个紧身衣男束手无策
...versus one guy in a unitard.
我没说错吧
Am I correct?
你其实不用等我的
You don't have to wait up for me.
- 我要等 - 真的不用
- Yes, I do. - No, you don't.
用 要等
Yes, I do.
- 好吧 - 你去哪儿了
- Okay. - Where were you?
去外面
I was out.
鸡蛋买了吗
Did you get the eggs?
没 我忘记买了
Nope. Forgot the eggs.
我现在去买
I'm gonna get them now.
不用 你不需要去买
No, you most certainly will not.
都这么晚了
Not at this hour.
看着我 彼得
Look at me, Peter.
把帽子摘下来 看着我
Take off the damn hood and look at me.
彼得 你去哪儿了
Peter. Where do you go?
是谁吧你打成这样
Who does this to you?
快去睡觉吧 梅姨妈
Please go to sleep, Aunt May.
- 告诉我 - 梅姨妈 求你了去睡吧
- Please tell me. - Aunt May, please...
求你了 求你 去睡吧
...please, please go to sleep.
我睡不着 你不明白吗 我睡不着
I can't sleep. Don't you understand? I can't sleep.
彼得 听我说
Peter, listen to me.
秘密是要付出代价的
Secrets have a cost.
没有例外
They're not for free.
现在没有 以后也不会有
Not now, not ever.
跨种族遗传开始起作用了
Cross-species genetics is finally working.
我用了蜥蜴的DNA来帮助弗莱迪那条腿的再生
I've used the lizard DNA to help Freddy regrow that limb.
这是个奇迹
It's a miracle.
不 这是努力研究的成功 也是希望
No, it's hard work and promise.
- 我们离灵长类动物实验更近了一步 - 他可没时间等你小步前进
- It's a step closer to the primate lab. - He doesn't have time for every little step.
小步
Little?
我只是想说他没法等了
I just mean he can't wait.
可是 他必须耐心等待
Well, he'll have to.
除非他想成为一只小白鼠
Unless he wants to be a lab rat.
我所说的
That's not what...
不是这个意思
...I'm saying.
所以你的意思是
So, what are you saying?
你得开始做人体实验了
You have to start human trials.
马上
Now.
不 我不想 也不会这么做
No, I don't, and no, I won't.
- 那么 他就必死无疑了 - 人总有一死
- Well, then he's going to die. - People die.
诺曼?奥斯本也不例外
Even Norman Osborn.
我话还没说完
We are not finished.
人体实验
Human trials?
你准备上哪儿去找自愿实验者
Where are you going to find the people to volunteer?
就说是一个流感疫苗 谁在乎
As far as anyone's concerned, it's for a flu shot.
我觉得可以先在退伍军人医院里试试
I might think the Veterans Hospital is a place to start.
你在开玩笑吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
我不觉得我在开玩笑
I don't think I am.
现在才觉得震惊愤怒可有点迟了
It's a little late for shock and indignation.
迟了15年
About 15 years late.
我完全不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
理查德?帕克把这番话说得正义凛然
Richard Parker wore it well.
可你说出来就显得虚伪做作了 和当初一样
On you, it's a cheap suit, as it was then.
这和我没关系
I had nothing to do with that.
你对他的儿子彼得也这么说的么
Is that what you told his son, Peter?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're saying.
你不知道 还是你不想知道
You don't know, or you don't wanna know?
让我来提醒你
I'll remind you what happened.
理查德?帕克也说过你刚才所说的那番话
Richard Parker said just about the same thing then that you are saying now.
你的时间不多了 康纳斯博士
The clock is ticking, Dr. Connors.
我
I....
我不会做
I won't.
好吧
Fine.
总之方程式现在是属于公司的
The formula is ours now anyway.
和你那条做梦都想长出来的胳膊说再见吧
Say goodbye to that arm you have dreamed of.
你被开除了
I'm shutting you down.
明早之前把你的办公室腾出来
Have your office cleared out by the morning.
你那些小宠物也可以带走
Your toys can be taken away too, you know.
对吧 弗莱迪
Right, Freddy?
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
最近还好么
How's it going?
你去哪儿
Where you headed?
- 周一 去玩场地自行车 - 噢 今天是周四
- Monday, B track. - Oh, it's Thursday.
- 今天周四 - 发生什么了
- It's Thursday? - What happened?
- 你说什么 - 你的眼睛 看上去有点淤青
- What? - Your eye, it looks bruised.
哦 是啊 不 我不
Oh, yeah, no, I don't....
可能是得了皮疹之类的
Maybe I got a rash or....
很严重啊 你去看校医了吗
It's bad. Have you gone to the nurse?
你喜欢吃柠檬鲈鱼吗
Do you like branzino?
就是 一种鱼
Like, a fish.
不不 我知道 我知道
No, no. I know. I know.
如果你愿意
Well, if you want...
你可以今晚八点去这个地方
...you can come to this address at 8:00 tonight.
我妈妈今晚做柠檬鲈鱼
My mom's making branzino.
那么
So....
哦 是公寓
It's apartment...
2016号 我没写房间号
...2016. I didn't write that part down.
我不知道为什么我
I don't know why l....
- 我记住了 - 哦 好的
- I'll remember it. - Oh, okay.
嗨
Hi.
你怎么上来的
How did you get out there?
消防梯
The fire escape.
你们的门卫有点吓人
Your doorman's intimidating.
这可是20层楼
It's 20 storeys.
嗯 没事的
Yeah. It's all right.
- 这是你的房间 - 嗯 这是我房间
- This is your room. - Yes, this is my room.
书
Books.
还有鞋
Shoes.
哦 对了
Oh, hey....
我给你妈妈带了
I got your mom...
这些
...these.
哦 真漂亮
Oh, lovely.
- 很美 对吧 - 很美
- Beautiful, right? - Beautiful.
他们本来挺好的
They were nice.
- 不 很美 - 不好意思
- No, they're beautiful. - I'm sorry.
不 非常美 它们捆得还挺牢
No, it's impressive. They actually held together very well.
我还是自己留着吧
I'm gonna keep these.
你包里是西装吗
You have your suit in there?
西装
My suit?
晚餐时候穿的正装 难道你就...
It's for dinner. Are you gonna...
你就穿身上这件吗
Are you gonna wear that?
- 有点 - 亲爱的
- That's-- - Hey, hon.
你一定是彼得
You must be Peter.
爸爸 这是彼得
Dad, this is Peter.
很高兴见到您 先生
Nice to meet you, sir.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
晚饭已经好了
Dinner's ready.
希望你喜欢柠檬鲈鱼
Hope you like branzino.
谁不喜欢呢
Who doesn't?
艾玛 我是柯特
Emma, it's Curt.
- 他在吗 - 不好意思博士 他不在
- ls he there? - I'm afraid not, doctor.
司机送他去布鲁克林的退伍军人医院了
The car is taking him to the Veterans Hospital in Brooklyn.
不 他不能去 艾玛
No. He can't, Emma.
你必须阻止他 他
You have to stop him. He--
我会的 但上桥的时候我经常会联系不到他
I would, but I always lose him on the bridge.
我跟您保证拉达博士会尽快给您回电话的
I'll make sure Dr. Ratha returns your call as soon as possible.
我要去河对面的霍尔顿大道 我赶时间
I'm going to Holton Avenue, across the river. I'm in a hurry.
好的 你要走隧道还是过桥
You want me to take the tunnel or the bridge?
过桥 从桥上走
Bridge! Take the bridge.
好吧 我们从桥上走
All right, we'll do that.
先生
Hey, you all right...
你没事吧
...back there?
你扭到手了吗
You tweaking...
先生
...man?
开你的车
Just drive.
好吧
Okay.
你不太会吃这个鱼
You're having trouble there?
鱼头朝那边
The head goes on the other--
去帮格温的朋友切一下他的鱼
Help Gwen's friend with his fish.
哦 我
Oh, l....
我不知道怎么弄
I got no idea.
第一次吃吧
First time.
- 柠檬鲈鱼 - 乔治
- Branzino. - George.
- 给我们讲讲你今天过得怎么样 - 你抓到了那个蜘蛛人嘛
- Tell us about your day. - Did you catch that spider guy yet?
没有 我们还没抓住他
No, we didn't catch him yet.
不过我们会的 他是一个闲的无聊
But we will. He's an amateur...
喜欢在大半夜袭击市民的人
...who's assaulting civilians in the dead of night.
他笨手笨脚 留下不少线索
He's clumsy, he leaves clues...
但他仍旧是个危险人物
...but he's still dangerous.
他袭击平民吗
He's assaulting people?
我不觉得是这样
I'm not sure.
我的意思是 我看了那段视频
I mean, I saw that video...
是他和那个偷车贼
...with him and the car thief, and....
我觉得大部分人会认为他在
I think most people would say that he was...
做公益服务
...providing a public service.
那大部分人就是错的
Most people would be wrong.
如果我想要那个偷车贼从那条街上消失 他就再也不会出现
If I wanted the car thief off the street, he'd already be off the street.
那他怎么还在那儿
So why wasn't he then?
我来给你讲明白点
Let me illuminate you.
那个偷车贼引出可以帮我们引出
The car thief was leading us to the people who run...
幕后集团 我们已经跟进了半年
...the operation. It's a six-month-long sting.
这是战略 我相信你明白这个词
It's called strategy. I'm sure you're aware of the term?
- 你在学校里听过这个词吗 - 是的
- You've heard about that in school? - Yeah.
很好
Good.
我知道
I know.
- 他显然不知道你这个计划 - 你好像对这件事
- He didn't know you had a plan. - You seem to know...
知道挺多的 你是不是了解什么内幕
...a lot about this. Know something we don't?
- 我说你到底是哪头的 - 我哪头也不是
- I mean, Whose side are you on? - I'm not on anyone's side.
我在网上看到一段视频
I saw a video on the lnternet--
你在网上看到一段视频
You saw the video on the lnternet.
- 好吧 那我们可以结案了 - 哦 不
- Well, then the case is closed. - Well, no.
如果你看过那个视频
If you watch the video--
也许我能发你条链接
Maybe send you a link?
看起来他真心想帮助别人
It looks like he's trying to help.
在网上他已然被人刻画为一个英雄
On the lnternet he's being made out to look like a hero.
不 不
No, no.
我不是说他是个英雄
I'm not saying he's a hero.
- 那你的意思呢 - 他只是想帮助别人
- What are you trying to say? - He's trying to help.
他是在试着做一些警察做不到的事情
He's trying to do something the police can't.
警察做不到的事情
Something the police can't?
- 我也不知道 - 你以为我们整天在干嘛
- I don't know. - What do you think we do?
围成圈一边吃甜甜圈
Sit around eating doughnuts...
一边摸自己屁股吗
...with our thumbs planted up our asses?
- 乔治 乔治 - 爸爸
- George. George. - Daddy.
- 摸啥 - 霍华德
- Up your what? - Howard.
我觉得他的立场和您一样
He stands for what you stand for.
保护那些无辜的人不受坏人欺负
Protecting innocent people from bad guys.
我的立场就是捍卫法律和秩序 那是我的立场
I stand for law and order. That's what I stand for.
明白么 我戴着警徽
Okay? I wear a badge.
而那家伙戴着面具 像个亡命之徒
This guy wears a mask like an outlaw.
他捉的那群犯人看起来都是一个模子里印出来
He's hunting down criminals that all look the same...
就好像他是为了报私仇
...Iike he's got some sort of personal vendetta.
而非保护无辜的人 帕克先生
But he's not protecting innocent people, Mr. Parker.
我们出去走走吧 彼得
Let's get some air, Peter.
- 爸爸 我们需要谈谈 - 是的 我们得谈谈
- Dad, we need to talk. - Yes, we do.
感谢您的邀请 如果言语有冒犯
Thank you for having me. I'm sorry...
请不要见怪 这并非我本意
...if I insulted you. It was not my intention.
- 没关系 - 柠檬鲈鱼很美味 斯泰茜夫人
- You're welcome. - Branzino was real good, Mrs. Stacy.
- 谢谢您 - 不用客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 爸爸 - 嗯
- Dad. - Yeah?
刚才真要命
Well, that was something.
很抱歉 我刚才还以为他会逮捕我呢
I'm sorry. I thought he was going to arrest me at one point.
不 我不会让他逮捕你的
No, I wouldn't have let him arrest you.
- 你的脸怎么了 - 我有些事要告诉你
- What happened to your face? - I wanna tell you something.
好啊
Okay.
我被咬了
I've been bitten....
我也是
So have l.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 好吧 好吧 我真的要告诉你一件事
Okay, okay, okay. I gotta tell you this one thing.
这件事是关于
I gotta tell you this thing about...
- 正义使者和偷车贼的 - 哦 我听着
- ...the vigilante and the car thief. - Oh, okay.
什么
What?
- 不 不 不 - 我不想谈那个了
- No, no, no. - I don't want to talk about that.
不提了 我不说了
Forget that. I won't talk about that.
- 我来谈谈我自己 行吗 - 关于你的什么
- I'm gonna talk about me, okay? - What about you?
这不可 我希望我可以
It's impo-- I wish I could just--
我说不出口 太难表达了
I can't. It's hard to say.
你只管说
Just say it.
- 我不知道 - 说吧
- I don't know. - Say it.
什么 什么
What? What?
关于什么
What?
好吧 不说这个了
Okay, then forget it.
你
You...
- 你就是蜘蛛侠 - 别闹
- You're Spider-Man. - Shut up.
格温
Gwen?
Gwen....
你爸爸想让你进去
Your father wants you to come inside.
好的
Okay.
- 行吗 - 没问题
- Okay? - Yeah.
格温
Gwen.
这就来了
I'm coming.
噢 我有麻烦了
Oh, I'm in trouble.
你可以
Will you please...
去看看发生什么了吗 阿尔弗雷德
...find out what is going on, Alfred?
好极了
Excellent.
喂
Hey!
喂 怎么了
Hey! What is that?
- 哦 上帝啊 - 我不知道
- Oh, my God! - I don't know!
回到车里去
Get back in the car!
救命
Help!
我来了
Incoming!
快来个人帮帮我
Somebody help!
救命 我的孩子被困住了
Help me! My kid is trapped!
我要爸爸
I want my dad!
爸爸
Dad!
- 嘿 嘿 嘿 - 救我
- Hey, hey, hey. - Help!
嘿 小家伙
Hey, buddy.
- 冷静下来 - 走开
- It's okay. - Get away.
- 救命 - 嘿 你瞧
- Help! - Hey, look.
我只是一个普通人 好吗
Just a normal guy, all right?
想拿着这个吗
Wanna hold this?
拿着我的面具
Hold my mask.
就这样
All right.
你叫什么
What's your name?
杰克
Jack?
- 是的 - 让我把你从这儿弄出来
- Yes. - Let's get you out of here.
好的 你稳住 别动
Okay, stay very still.
就这样
All right.
好 我抓住你了
Okay, I got you.
好 你看
Okay, look.
我会解开安全带 等会儿你就
I'll undo the belt. You hold on...
紧紧抓住前面的座位 我数三声
...to that seat in front of you. On three?
- 好的 - 开始了 一 二 三
- All right. - Okay, one, two, three.
看 很容易吧 你做得很棒
See how easy that was? You did a great job.
没问题了 好了
All right, okay.
杰克 快爬上去
Jack, climb now.
- 我害怕 - 你可以的
- I can't. - Yes, you can.
戴上面具
Put it on, the mask.
它会给你力量
It's gonna make you strong.
杰克 相信我
Jack, trust me.
戴上它
Put it on.
就是这样 伙计 就这样 就是这样
There you go. That's it. That's it, buddy.
就现在 快爬
Okay, now, climb.
加把劲 杰克
Come on, Jack.
就当帮我个忙
Do me a favour.
爬快点儿 行吗
A little faster, okay, bud?
你做得很好 伙计 你做得可棒了
You're doing great, buddy. You're doing great.
就是那样 保持住
That's it. Keep coming.
爬上来
Keep it coming.
继续爬
Keep coming.
不
No!
杰克 哦 天啊
Jack. Oh, God.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
你没事吧
You okay?
我的儿子 我的儿子
My son. My son.
儿子
Oh, my son.
我的儿子
My son.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man.
太美了
Beautiful.
冷静 孩子
Settle down, guys.
冷静 冷静下来 孩子
Settle down, boys. Settle down.
- 就这样 - 听着 昨晚大约
- Come on. - Listen. At approximately...
9点左右 威廉斯堡大桥发生了一起意外
...9 p.m. Iast night, an incident took place on the Williamsburg Bridge.
所发生的事情大部分都仅仅是推测而已
Much of what occurred is speculation...
然而 不少人目睹了一起犯罪案件
...at this point. However, several eyewitnesses...
并且通过初步调查
... to the crime, as well as our own preliminary findings, have...
我们明确有一个人
...positively placed...
出现在犯罪现场
... one individual at the scene.
这就是我为什么
Which is why, this morning...
会在今天造成申请逮捕证
...I am issuing a warrant...
去追捕所谓的蒙面正义使者 蜘蛛侠
... for the masked vigilante known as Spider-Man.
最后 市议会成员在最初四次会议上会见了
And lastly, city council members met with homeowners and airport officials...
房产所有人和机场官员
... in the first of four meetings....
实在太美了
It's so beautiful.
可是它会咬人
Knows how to bite though.
还有谁知道这件事
Who else knows about this?
只有你
Just you.
真的吗
Really?
嘿 你没
Hey, you don't....
你没相信警方的话吧 没有吧
You don't believe what the police are saying, do you?
当然没有
Of course not.
你不害怕吗
Does it scare you?
你能做什么呢
What you can do?
不
No.
那个桥上的东西到底长什么样
What did that thing on the bridge look like?
很大 比人类要大很多
It was real big. Too big to be human.
你要低调一些
You gotta lay low.
不 我不能那样做
No, can't do that.
你必须得那样
You've got to.
我是说 为什么
I mean, why...
因为昨晚的事
Because of last night.
桥上的那些人
Those people on the bridge.
攻击他们的东西是致命的
Whatever was attacking them would have killed them.
所以
So...
我必须抓住它
...I gotta go after it.
那不是你的职责
That's not your job.
也许是呢
Maybe it is.
我真喜欢跟你接吻
I really liked kissing you.
你的吻技太棒了
You're an amazing kisser.
你知道 这个吻
Well, you know, it was--
对我来说也很棒
It was good for me too.
是吗
Yeah?
那是谁干的
Who did that?
你好
Hello!
偷偷摸摸可不好
It's not nice to snoop.
我给所有员工放了一周假
I gave everyone the week off.
原来如此
Yeah.
你不是应该在学校吗
Shouldn't you be at school?
不 我现在没课
No, I got a free track.
我想问你一个问题
I wanted to ask you a question.
捕食者是怎样
How would a predator...
追踪到爬行动物的
...track a reptile?
哦 它们不需要 大部分爬行动物
Oh, they don't. Most reptiles are at the top...
是位于食物链的上层
...of their food chain.
它们是主宰者
Kings of their domain.
他们也有弱点
They gotta have vulnerabilities.
为什么突然对冷血动物产生兴趣
Why the sudden interest in the cold-blooded?
就是问问而已
Just asking a question.
我有一些功课
I got school stuff.
涉及到生物学内容
Biology profiles to do.
所以是因为
So because of the cold blood...
这些冷血动物会对突然的温度变化做出反应
...would they react to changes in temperatures?
你得先捉住一只
You'd have to catch one first.
你有听说过吗 有谣言说在纽约出现了新物种
Did you know there's a rumour of a new species in New York?
美丽并且巨大
Beautiful and quite large.
你是怎样知道的 你看过吗
What do you know about it? You seen it?
没看过 但这又不是什么秘密
No, it's not yet classified.
如果它受到威胁
But it can be aggressive...
它会变得好战
...if threatened.
博士 你还好吧
Doc, you all right?
从没现在这么好过 彼得 从来没有
Never been better, Peter. Never been better.
现在 如果你不介意的话
Now, if you'll excuse me.
我得请你离开了 我正在着手新项目
Afraid I have to ask you to leave. I have a new project...
我需要一个人呆着
...I'm working on. I need to be alone.
好的 好的 好的
Good. Good, good.
很好
Good.
别担心 帕克先生 我很快回来
Don't worry, Mr. Parker. I'll be back.
好事情即将发生了
Wonderful things are coming.
好事情
Wonderful things.
弗莱德
Fred?
市长先生 如果有一只巨大的恐龙
Mr. Mayor, if there was a giant dinosaur...
四次乱窜 我一定会第一时间通知您的
...running around you would be the first to know.
所以告诉你的儿子 他好好休息了 行吗
So tell your son he can rest easy, all right?
好的 我们都如此
Yeah. You and me both, sir.
好 拜拜
Okay. Bye-bye.
帕克先生 你为什么
Mr. Parker, why are you...
- 没在学校 - 我没课
- ...not in school? - Got a free track.
好吧 是这样 我不能来
Okay, well, I do not.
你快点把话说完吧
So make your point quickly.
没问题 在曼哈顿四处乱跑的可能不是恐龙
Fine, there may not be a dinosaur running around.
是更危险的东西 我知道是谁
There is something more dangerous, and I know who.
- 你知道是谁 - 柯蒂斯·康纳斯博士
- You know who? - Dr. Curtis Connors.
- 他是个生物学家 - 奥斯的那位
- He's a biochemist. - Of Oscorp?
- 没错 - 康纳斯博士
- That's right. - Dr. Connors...
曾经是我女儿的导师 你说的就是他吗
...who's my daughter's mentor. Is that who?
- 就是他 - 明白了
- That's the one. - Okay.
最近 康纳斯博士帮格温写了一封大学推荐信
Recently, Dr. Connors gave Gwen a college recommendation.
那文笔太美了 看得我都哭了
It was beautiful. When I read it, I cried.
而你现在要我相信
You would have me believe that he...
他cos成恐龙的样子到处跑
...is running around dressed up like a dinosaur?
不是cos 也不是恐龙 他是把自己改造成一只巨大的蜥蜴
Not dressing up and not a dinosaur. He has transformed himself into a lizard.
我先问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
我看起来像东京的市长吗
Do I look like the mayor of Tokyo to you?
我在告诉你千真万确的事实
I'm telling you the absolute truth.
这个男人一生都在做交叉物种的研究
This man has worked for his whole life on cross-species genetics.
他没了一条胳膊 所以努力想让它重新长出来 但那方程式并不均衡
He lost an arm, he tried to grow it back, but the equation was imbalanced.
导致他变成了一只蜥蜴人 他在使用蜥蜴的基因
He has turned into a lizard. He's using lizard DNA.
他非常危险 而且他现在在策划一些可怕的事 我很清楚
He is dangerous, and he is planning something horrific. I know. I know.
好吧 好吧 我明白了
Okay. All right, I get it.
我们接下来就这么做
Here's what we'll do.
你回去陪东京市民游山玩水
You'll go back to hanging out with the citizens of Tokyo.
而我就回去保护我们这座
I'm gonna go back to protecting the citizens...
美丽的城市
...of this fine, fair city of ours.
巴特勒警官 你可以帮我送帕克先生
Sergeant Butler, please escort Mr. Parker...
- 回学校吗 - 斯特西队长 我并不是来捣乱的
- ...back to school. - Captain Stacy, I'm not messing around.
把他带过来询问他 打电话叫他来 一定要叫他来
Just bring him in. Just call him in. You have to call him in.
他是个危险人物
He is a danger to everybody.
- 拜托 相信我 - 我们走吧
- Just, please, listen to me. - Let's go.
吉米
Jimmy.
把手头上有的柯蒂斯·康纳斯的所有东西都给我
Get me everything we have on Dr. Curtis Connors.
- 行吗 现在就要 - 当然
- Okay? Right away. - Yeah.
实验对象 柯蒂斯·康纳斯博士
Subject: Dr. Curtis Connors.
体温89.7
Current temperature: 89.7.
稳定48小时
Steady for 48 hours.
血液分析显示 淋巴细胞和单核细胞的文本
Blood panels reveal lymphocyte and monocyte readings...
都包含以往的主体的信息
...consistent with subject's past.
凝血速度迅速提高
Clotting rate vastly improved.
肌肉反应 力量
Marked enhancement...
灵活性
...in muscle response...
有显著提升
...strength and elasticity.
视力得到相应改进
Eyesight similarly improved.
实验对象无需再佩戴视力矫正镜片
Subject no longer requires corrective lenses.
这不是寻找治疗疾病的方法
This is no longer about curing ills.
这是
This is about...
寻找完美物种之路
...finding perfection.
尝试阻止旧病复发
In attempt to redress regenerative relapse...
剂量增加到200毫克
...dosage has been increased to 200 milligrams.
你曾阻止我一次
You stopped me once.
这一次 你不能再阻扰我了
You won't stop me again.
我一天比一天强大
I'm getting stronger every day!
噢 真要命
Oh, that sucked.
彼得?帕克
Peter Parker.
进来
Come in.
你本应该
You should maybe...
考虑光明正大地进来
...consider coming in through the lobby.
另外 我爸爸总觉得
Also, my father is under the impression...
- 你是时候该去看看心理医生 - 哦 真的吗
- ...that you require psychiatric attention. - Oh, really?
彼得
Peter.
发生什么了
What happened?
另外一个人比我还惨
You should see the other guy.
另一个人 他突然从人变成了一只巨大的蜥蜴
The other guy, in this instance, being a giant mutant lizard.
嘿 格温 甜心
Hey, Gwen, honey.
你想要杯可可吗
Do you want cocoa?
霍华德泡了一些
Howard's making some.
不 爸爸 我不想喝
No, Dad, I do not want cocoa.
另外 我已经17岁了
Honestly, I'm 17 years old.
好吧
Okay.
可是我记得上周不知道是谁说 她总是幻想住在巧克力房子里
I remembered somebody saying her fantasy was to live in a chocolate house.
那是不现实的
Well, that's impractical.
而且会变胖的
And fattening.
巧克力房子
Chocolate house.
- 抱歉爸爸 - 没事
- Sorry, Dad. - It's good.
我不能喝可可 因为我现在有些事忙着
I can't have cocoa right now because I'm work--
我在忙着
I'm doing this....
我痛经了
I have cramps.
我现在很难受 而且有点儿
I feel kind of pukey and just sort of....
- 就是有点情绪波动 就像在哭一样 - 好吧 我知道了
- Like, emotional. I keep crying. - It's okay. Good.
- 就这样 - 痛得很厉害
- Good. - It's brutal.
你是不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
- 那种感觉就像 - 明白了
- It's, like, bad. - Got it.
- 谢谢理解 - 好了
- Thanks, Daddy. - All right.
放松点 见习骑师
Easy, Bug Boy.
你刚刚叫我什么
What'd you call me?
我不会有事的
I'm going to be all right.
- 有事 有事 - 没事 没事
- No. No. - Yes. Yes.
我知道这是什么
I know what this is.
什么
What is it?
每天 我记得的每一天 我爸爸
Every day, for as long as I can remember, my father...
每天早上的时候都会出门
...has left every morning...
他把徽章别在胸口
...and he's put a badge on his chest...
腰上戴着他的枪
...and strapped a gun to his hip.
然后每天 自从记事开始
And every day, for as long as I can remember...
我一直担心他就这样一去不回
...I haven't known if he was gonna make it home.
我懂的
I got you.
好吗
Okay?
不过 我必须阻止他
I gotta stop him, though.
我不得不这样做 因为是我创造了他
I have to, because I created him.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
我把方程式给了他
I gave him an equation...
是我造成了这一切
...that made all of this possible.
我爸爸之前研究过一些东西 你知道
Something my father had been working on, you know.
秘密地 现在我明白他为何要保密了
Secretly. Now I realise why he kept it a secret.
关键在于 这是我的责任
Point is, this is my responsibility.
我必须弥补这个过错
I have to fix it.
彼得
Peter.
嘿
Hey.
我们出去透透气
Let's get out of here.
就是去透透气
Let's just get out of here.
就一会 好吗
Just for a minute. Can we?
- 不 不行 - 来吧 没关系的
- No. No. - Yeah. Yes.
- 来吧 - 真的不行
- Yes. - No.
真没事的
Yes.
如果被我父母看见 我就死定了
If my parents see me leaving, I'm dead.
你父母不会看见你离开的
Your parents aren't gonna see you leaving.
彼得?帕克
Peter Parker.
蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man.
我不是唯一需要
I'm not the one who needs...
帮助的人
...help.
不会再感到孤单
There will be no more loneliness...
不会再被孤立
...no more outcasts.
物种广泛分布可以促进
Species-wide distribution could enhance...
人类进化过程
...humanity on an evolutionary scale.
适者生存
One has to adapt to survive.
因此 如果可以像蛇那样蜕变 也许我就可以
"That, changing like the snake, I might be free...
摆脱肉体对我的禁锢
...to cast off flesh wherein I dwell confined."
你已经放弃了吗 终于知道
Would you give it all up after all you know...
你的能力所及
...you can do?
你所感受到的这些力量
All the power you feel.
我可以拯救
I can save...
他们
... them!
我不允许你
You won't get in...
打乱我的计划
... the way of my plan...
彼得?帕克
...Peter Parker!
走 快走
Go. Go!
你无处可逃 彼得
Nowhere to hide, Peter.
这些流离失所的
All these souls...
灵魂
...Iost and alone.
我可以拯救他们
I can save them.
我可以治愈他们
I can cure them.
你不应该阻止我
There's no need to stop me...
彼得
...Peter.
你脑子糊涂了 博士
You're not thinking straight, doc.
快停止 这并不是你
Stop this. This isn't you.
我们谈谈吧
Let's talk this out.
博士
Doc!
噢小子
Oh, boy.
你不想谈谈吗
You don't want to talk?
这下你会懂的
There you go.
别
Don't...
逼
...make me...
我
...have to...
伤害你
...hurt you!
真是恶心
That is disgusting.
格温
Gwen.
- 我会把你从这儿扔到窗外 - 什么
- I'm gonna throw you out the window. - What?
有人变成
Somebody's been...
蜥蜴怪物啦
a bad lizard.
这位是纽约警局的威廉副队长
This is Lieutenant Williams from the New York City...
我们已经将这座大楼包围了
...Police Department. We've got this building surrounded.
前进前进 快
Alpha, let's move ahead. Go!
- 嘿 - 你在哪儿
- Hey. - Where are you?
我很好 我没事
I'm fine. I'm okay.
我正在下水道里追踪他 我会在他伤人之前阻止他
I'm in the sewer, tracking him. I gotta stop him before anyone gets hurt.
但我们需要解药
But we need an antidote.
- 你知道怎样制作血清吗 - 我一直在做这个
- Do you know how to run a serum? - I do it all the time.
好的 太棒了 实在太棒了 我需要你去奥斯集团
Okay, great. Okay, I need you to go to Oscorp.
你要去找到交叉物种的文件 那是蓝色的血清
I need you to access the cross-species file. It's a blue serum.
12389号档案
File 1 2389.
好的 明白了
Okay, got it.
我这就去
On my way.
作为一个科学家 我终其一生都在创造一个没有缺陷的世界
I spent my life as a scientist trying to create a world without weakness...
没人会被抛弃
... without outcasts.
我想创造更强壮的人类
I sought to create a stronger human being...
但这并不可能
...but there's no such thing.
人类都只是软弱 可怜
Human beings are weak, pathetic, feeble-minded...
无力的动物
... creatures.
那为什么还要生而为人
Why be human at all...
当我们可以变得
... when we can be so...
更好
...much more?
更快 更强
Faster. Stronger.
更聪敏
Smarter.
这是我给你们的礼物
This is my gift to you.
奥斯
Oscorp.
- 斯特西队长 - 什么
- Captain Stacy! - What?
我们确定目标位置了 长官 那蜥蜴人正在朝
We have a confirmed sighting, sir. The Lizard's headed...
- 坚尼街车站走去 - 那蜘蛛侠呢
- ...toward Canal Street. - What about Spider-Man?
他在学校里面
Inside the high school.
我要抓住蜘蛛侠
I want that Spider-Man off the street.
蜥蜴这种生物放出生物剂
The lizard creature has released a biological agent.
制止他的行动都失败了
All efforts to stop him have failed...
他现在7号大街上往北走
...and he is now proceeding north on 7th Avenue. Over.
- 嗨 - 你在哪里
- Hi. - Where are you?
彼得 嗨 我在奥斯集团
Peter, hi. I'm at Oscorp.
你现在就离开那里
You have to get out of there now.
- 解毒剂正在制作中 - 噢 不 不
- The antidote is cooking. - No, no, no.
康纳斯在路上了 他很快就到你那里了
Connors is on the way. He's coming to you right now.
他需要那个放射设备 他想让整个城市都感染病毒
He needs the device. He's gonna infect the whole city!
只剩下8分钟了
Eight minutes left.
我都告诉你了 你还准备在那里待8分钟吗
You're gonna wait eight minutes after what I told you?
人们会死的
People are gonna to die.
这是命令 好吗
That is an order, okay?
我会把大家都带出来的
I'll get everybody out.
你根本就没有听
Did you hear wh...
格温 他妈的 你是认真的啊
Gwen! Gwen! You Mother Hubbard. Are you serious?
他朝南边走了
He's heading south.
停下 否则我们就开枪了
Stand down now, or we will open fire.
你已经被包围 你
You are surrounded. There is...
无法逃脱的
...no escape.
上 上
Go, go!
就位
Clear!
Clear up top!
就位 长官
Clear, sir!
各就各位 长官
All clear here, sir!
不许动
Freeze!
趴到地上
Down on the ground.
把你的手放到头后面
Your hands behind your head.
立刻
Now!
帕克
Parker.
它正在往奥斯集团走
It's headed to Oscorp!
你女儿现在就在那里
And your daughter's there right now.
你必须让我走
You gotta let me go.
停止射击
Hold your fire!
好吧 保罗 但如果没看见 我是不会相信的
Well, Paul, if I didn't see it, I wouldn't believe it.
我是不会冒险说这话 如果那个东西不是真的
I won't venture to say what it is crawling up...
往奥斯塔楼的北面爬上去
...the north side of the Oscorp Tower...
但记住 它不是人类 并且它十分强壮
...but clearly it is not human and it is very, very strong.
剩余时间 1分钟
Time remaining: one minute.
血浆准备完毕
Antidote complete.
天啊
Oh, man.
我们获得最新消息 这是刚刚才收到的
We're getting the latest details. This is just coming in.
纽约警察要求撤离
The New York Police Department...
第54大街南部的
...has called for a city-wide evacuation...
一切人员车辆
...everything south of 54th Street.
如果你在第54大街以南
If you are south of 54th Street...
请你立刻从那里离开
...you have to move out of the area immediately.
看起来 蜘蛛侠在前往奥斯集团赶去
Spider-Man appears to be heading towards Oscorp.
他看起来受伤了
He looks injured...
不知道他是否可以做到
...and it's really not clear if he's gonna make it.
就是这个人
That's the guy who...
在桥上救了我儿子
...saved my boy on the bridge.
特洛伊 他们让我们撤离
Troy, they're clearing us out.
市中心有什么事情发生了
Something bad's going down in Midtown.
嘿 你的朋友马修斯 是那个在第6大道开吊车的吗
Still friends with Matthews, that crane operator on 6th?
- 是的 - 让他接电话
- Yeah. - Get him on the phone for me.
警察正在疏散所有人
The cops are evacuating everybody.
快让他接电话
Get him on the phone for me.
嘿 查理 给我接通第54大街的Enriquez
Hey, Charlie, get me Enriquez on 54th Street!
- 我知道了 - 安吉洛 快过来
- You got it. - Angelo, get your mug over here.
沃斯基 你得加班了
Wolski! You're getting some overtime!
所有塔式起重机都在第6大街
All tower cranes on 6th...
把你们的吊臂伸过街道 吊杆调整到90度
...swing your jib arms over the avenue. Boom angles at 90 degrees.
这些大家伙成排的举高帮助蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man needs those big boys high and lined up.
给他提供畅通的道路 完毕
Let's give him a clear approach. Over.
加油 彼得
Come on, Parker.
嘿
Hey.
爸爸
Dad!
- 我要把这个给蜘蛛侠 - 快上车
- I have to get this to Spider-Man. - Get in.
- 它能阻止蜥蜴人 - 上车
- lt can stop the Lizard. - Get in the car.
- 你不明白 - 不 我明白
- You don't understand! - Yes, I do.
那个面具男是你的男朋友
Your boyfriend is a man of many masks.
我知道
I get it.
把它给我
Give me this.
你快上车
Get in the car.
一定别让他受伤
Please make sure he's okay.
加纳利装置正在初始化
Initialising Ganali device.
倒计时两分钟
Detonation in T-minus two minutes.
可怜的彼得?帕克
Poor Peter Parker.
没有妈妈 没有爸爸
No mother, no father...
连叔叔也没了
...no uncle.
多么孤单
All alone.
他不是一个人
He's not alone.
倒计时45秒
Detonation in T-minus 45 seconds.
嘿
Hey!
格温的礼物
Gift from Gwen.
我来对付它 你快去
I got this, Peter! Go!
倒计时
T-minus...
30秒
...30 seconds.
倒计时
Detonation in T-minus...
10秒
... 10 seconds.
不
No.
No!
警长
The captain.
Captain!
蜥蜴博士它
The Lizard.
没事了
It's okay.
我们阻止了他
We stopped him.
那就好
Okay.
我带你离开这儿 来
Let's get you out of here. Come on.
慢点 慢点 慢点
Okay, okay, okay.
看着我 坚持住
Look at me. Stay with me.
- 救援队就快到了 - 你必须
- Help's on the way, okay? - You need to....
你必须在他们来之前 离开这里
You need to be gone when they get here.
好吗
Okay?
我不会走的
I'm not going anywhere.
我错怪你了 彼得
I was wrong about you, Peter.
这个城市需要你
This city needs you.
给你
Here.
你需要这个
You're gonna need this.
会有人对你怀有敌意
You're gonna make enemies.
人们也因此而受到伤害
People will get hurt.
有时候甚至是那些你最亲近的人
Sometimes the people closest to you.
所以答应我一件事 好吗
So I want you to promise me something, okay?
别把格温牵扯进来
Leave Gwen out of it.
向我保证
Promise me that.
答应我
You promise me.
可怕的平静
An eerie calm...
笼罩了整个纽约市
...has set in over New York City.
似乎有一些粉状的
Apparently, some sort of...
雾化解毒剂
...aerosolised antidote was launched from...
从奥斯塔洒下 目测这些粉状物直接抵消了生物毒素
...Oscorp Tower, which seems to have counteracted the biotoxins.
曼哈顿下城区的居民可以回复平静
Residents of Lower Manhattan can rest peacefully...
在这次恐怖事件的策划者
...knowing that the alleged mastermind...
柯蒂斯·康纳斯教授已被逮捕
... of this terror plot, Dr. Curtis Connors, is behind bars.
约翰?奈尔斯
We've got John Niles...
在曼哈顿下城区为您播报
... on the street for a report in Lower Manhattan.
约翰 你看到了什么
John, what do you see?
亲爱的 没事了
Sweetheart, it's all right.
都会好的
It's all right.
都会好起来的
忙了一夜
Rough night.
一切都会好的
It's gonna be all right.
你去哪儿了
Where have you been?
我
I...
我父亲去世了
My father died.
刚刚举行了葬礼
There was a funeral.
他们鸣枪致敬 发表悼词
They shot off rifles and they made speeches.
两位老师也去了
Two of my teachers showed up.
弗莱舍 弗莱舍也去了
Flash...And Flash showed up.
除了你 所有人都去了
Everyone was there but you.
我不能
I can't
我不能去 我不能
I can't do this, I can't do this.
对不起
I'm sorry
我不能
I can't
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我不能再和你见面了
I can't see you any more.
我不能
I can't.
他让你答应他 是吧
He made you promise, didn't he?
从此远离我
To stay away from me.
我就能安全了
So I'd be safe.
多么美的女孩
What a pretty girl.
嗯
Yeah.
本恩叔叔也这么说过
that's what Uncle Ben said.
你约她出去了吗
Did you ask her out?
为什么
Why?
我不能这样做
I can't
为什么
Why?
和我在一起对她不会幸福
I'm just no good for her.
彼得?帕克 她只要和你在一起 就会幸福
Peter Parker, if there's one thing you are, it's good.
任何对此有怀疑的人都可以找我谈谈
Anyone has a problem with that can talk to me.
彼得 我知道最近事情多有不顺
Peter, I know things have been difficult lately,
我对此很抱歉
and I'm sorry about that.
我想我知道你的感受
I think I know what you're feeling.
从你还是个孩子的时候
Ever since you were a little boy,
你的生活就一直伴随着那么多的麻烦
you've been living with so many unresolved things.
好吧 曾经有人说过
Well, take it from an old man,
那些让我们陷入低谷的事
those things send us down the road,
也会成就我们
and make us who we are.
如果有人注定要成为伟大的人 那一定是你 孩子
And if anyone's destined for greatness, it's you son.
这是上天赐予你的礼物 你必须弄明白如何使用它们
You owe the world your gifts, you just have to figure out how to use them.
你要知道无论它将你带出多远
And know that wherever they take you,
我们都一直在这儿
we'll always be here.
所以 回家吧彼得
So come on home Peter.
你是我的英雄 我爱你
You're my hero and I love you.
- 早上好 帕克 - 嘿 还好吗
- Hello Parker. - Hey, how's it going?
进展不错 伙计
You're coming along, man.
这衣服真不错
That's a cool shirt.
是啊
Yeah,
那男的够牛
dude's crazy.
但是小妞都喜欢他
But chicks dig him.
我有一位教授曾经告诉过他的学生
I had a professor once who liked to tell his students that there were only
所有的小说都逃不脱十种剧情
ten different plots in all of fiction.
现在我告诉你们他错了 剧情只有一个
Well I'm here to tell you he was wrong, there is only one.
我是谁
Who am I?
帕克先生 你又迟到了
Mr. Parker, tardy again.
好吧 至少你还是来上课了
Well, at least we can always count on you.
对不起 瑞特女士 不会有下次了 我保证
Sorry Miss Ritter, it won't happen again, I promise.
别许你做不到的承诺 帕克先生
Don't make promises you can't keep, Mr. Parker.
嗯 但承诺是最好听的话
Yeah, but those are the best kind.
好了同学们 打开课本 我们从第一页开始
Okay class, open your books, let's begin on page 1.
你好 博士
Hello doctor.
- 你告诉那个男孩了吗 - 告诉他什么
- Did you tell the boy? - Tell him what?
关于他父亲的真相
Did you tell the boy the truth about his father?
- 没有 - 那真是太好了
- No. - Well that's very good.
现在差不多是时候了
So we'll let him be for now.
你该离他远点
You should leave him alone!